What do you want?
Why is this door locked, Andrew?
I'm getting ready for school.
Open this door, Andrew.
Listen to me.
No, you're drunk.
I'm what?
Excuse me?
I said unlock the door.
Andrew?
Dad, it is 7:30 in the a.m.,
and you are drunk.
Listen. You don't tell me if I'm drunk
or not, you little shit.
Aren't you?
What are you doing in there?
I'm filming this.
What?
I bought a camera,
and I'm filming everything
from here on out.
Mom?
Mom.
Hey.
Say hello to my new camera for me.
Who's the audience?
Just the millions of people
that are watching at home.
Do I look awful?
No, no, no, Mom.
You look...
You look great.
It's a nice camera.
Well, thanks Mom.
So...
Should I ask about, the camera or...
I don't know. I'm...
I'm filming things now.
I'm filming everything.
You're filming everything?
Yeah.
Ok.
God, make it stop.
Have you ever read any
Arthur Schopenhauer?
No.
What is Arthur Schopenhauer?
He's...
He's this philosopher
that I'm reading at the moment.
For school?
No, no.
Basically human beings have to recognize
themselves as beings of pure will.
Right?
Ok.
So all emotional and physical desires
can never be fulfilled.
So basically you're telling me
that I should give up on life.
Yes.
Ok.
Come on, man!
Oh, God.
I'll see you later.
Alright, dude. Peace.
Learning time.
Get out of the way.
Are you not coming in?
I'm gonna hang back a while, ok?
You're gonna be late for first period.
Yeah. I will pick you up after seventh.
This is my school.
I guess.
Ok.
Hey, you!
Hey, guy.
What? Ok. Ok.
Vote for Steve for senior class president.
Yeah, I got it.
This is where I eat lunch.
Out here on the bleachers.
Hi.
Hey.
Could you not videotape us, please?
It's really creepy.
No, I wasn't.
Hi!
This is the hallway where my locker is.
What is this?
What's up, Detmer?
You should be on television.
Man, you're on a film, man.
Pretty on camera.
Smile, man, you look pretty.
You gonna cry? You gonna cry?
Sean, come on.
Give it back.
You want your camera?
Piece of shit from, like, 2004?
Here you go.
Here she is.
In one piece.
Guys.
Almost.
Assholes!
There's a party tonight.
Ok.
Haven Hills.
Wait. I thought Haven Hills
was closed.
It's abandoned, yeah.
What, you don't want to go?
No.
When was the last time you went to a party?
I don't go to parties.
You're a senior. You are a senior.
Just come.
I'll think about it, ok?
Ok.
But when we go tonight...
Andrew can I give you like a pro tip?
What?
Maybe leave your camera at home.
Why?
Because it's a little weird.
It serves a purpose.
I'm...
I'm just trying to be
a good cousin here, ok?
This is me being your friend
and telling you,
you should probably...
not take the camera to a party.
Ok.
This is my street.
And those are the official
douche bags of my street.
What the hell's that?
Oh, great.
Hey! What you doing?
Hey!
Andrew!
No, I wasn't...
Don't film me, Detmer!
Don't film me.
Run to your house, bitch!
This is where I eat lunch.
Out here on the bleachers.
What do you want?
When I say open that door,
you open the door. You got it?
Finish your goddamn homework.
Matt, are you sure it's here?
Dude, it's here. Calm down, ok?
There it is.
Oh, yeah.
Look a rave.
Look a nerd with a camera.
What?
Just don't follow me
around all night, ok?
What do you mean?
I thought...
I thought you wanted
me to come with you.
Yeah I did, I did.
But just go and...
do your own thing for once, ok?
Have a beer, talk to people.
I don't drink.
Hey!
Excuse me.
What are you filming for?
I don't...
What?
I can't hear you.
I'm just filming.
Cool. Cool.
I'm filming for my blog.
Andrew!
You should check it out.
Andrew.
It's actually...
Hey. Hey, Casey.
Hey.
How you doing?
I'm good. I'm good.
This is pretty lame, right?
Why is it lame?
You know, Jung said
parties are just...
people's way of
seeking widespread validation.
I'm not one to...
clamor to be cool, you know.
Way to put an analytical psychology
spin on this barn party, Matt.
That's awesome.
Awesome.
You're awesome.
Hey, Matt.
Hey, what did Jung say
about glow sticks?
You filming my girlfriend?
Yes or no?
No, I... I'm not filming anything.
I'm just filming the party.
Ok.
I should break your bitch-ass nose.
You know that?
No, I wasn't...
Don't talk back to me.
Bitch.
Ok.
Andrew?
Andrew.
With the camera.
Can we...
Can we use that thing?
What?
We found the craziest shit,
and we got to get it on tape.
It's not...
What's up, man?
You ok?
Yeah, I'm... I'm Andrew.
Ok. I'm Steve.
Steve Montgomery.
Yeah, I know.
Really?
Matt and I were just hanging out,
and we found this cool...
this thing.
Wait. You're with Matt?
You might want to get it on tape.
No, I just... I don't really.
Dude, just come on. just...
Just come get it on tape, it'll be cool.
I don't know.
Trust me.
Alright.
Yeah, man.
You know there are, like,
tons of girls around here, right?
And you're all by yourself,
next to a tree?
I'm just really picky.
Listen, I really don't think...
Is there a light on that thingl
like on the camera?
Yeah, here.
What were you guys doing out here?
A bunch of people were out here because
we were, like, obsessed with the thing.
What thing?
You'll see.
Oh, that's... that's right!
Andrew Detmer!
I remember you from homeroom,
freshman year.
You always had that gray zip-up hoodie.
Garetty!
You remember that?
Yeah, I got a...
I got a thing for faces, which is why
I'm going into politics.
Ironically enough,
because I'm so ridiculously hi...
Down here!
There we go.
Garetty, what's up?
I see you!
Matt!
You see me?
Yeah, where did everybody go?
They left! They left! Come on.
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Do you see that?
Guys, what is that?
Do you see it? Is that the camera?
Yeah, I got him!
Do you guys know how to get back from here?
Is it still making that sound?
Yes. Did you tell Andrew?
Andrew, it's making that sound, dude.
Dude, come and listen to this.
Listen to this.
No, no, no, no.
You got to get in. Ok, ok.
You got to get close, like literally almost in the hole.
Ok, don't push me. Just don't push me.
Check this shit out. We're not gonna push you in.
We're just trying to get it on camera.
Listen. Can you hear that?
What...
I think we got it.
Wait, how creepy is that?
Is this sound coming up?
I don't know, I mean probably
it's pretty loud, right?
Hello!
Alright, dude. We're going inside.
I'm going back, come on you guys?
I got to know.
Matt, seriously, we...
Hey, wait, wait. Steve!
Steve!
Oh, shit! He's a ninja.
Matt!
Matt, Matt, Matt.
What are you doing?
Are you serious?
Andrew, can you give me some light?
Matt, don't be an idiot.
Matt!
Matt, you're my ride home!
Hello?
Smells terrible. You guys!
Matt!
Hello?
Andrew's such a pussy.
Alright, does it go down
much deeper or what?
Yeah man, it goes really, really far.
Andrew, bring the light.
Look at the walls.
It's like a straight shot down.
Probably already come
like 40 or 50 feet.
Yeah, just don't talk about it, ok?
You ever...
You ever heard of Plato's
Allegory of the Cave?
I don't know, Matt.
Let's just get this over with.
Oh, Shit!
Holy shit.
The hell is that?
Matt, I'm not kidding.
I can't breathe.
Come on.
Andrew, look at this.
What...
Can you believe this?
Matt.
What am I looking at?
Shit!
I am freaking out right now!
Matt!
Can we get out of here, please?
Is it showing up
on the camera like that?
I don't know, man.
It's messing with it.
I don't really want to film...
Dude, I'll buy you a new one.
Touch one.
Matt!
Matt, look at this!
What?
Look at this!
Dude, what is...
Dude, no way!
It's changing colors!
Oh, my God.
Must be reacting to heat.
I can't hear you over that.
This is awesome.
Oh dude, your nose!
Steve, Steve! Steve!
Steve! Steve!
Matt, dude, put your phone down.
Turn it off.
Ok, ok, ok.
Steve, you too.
Alright. We have to document this.
Ok, are you guys ready?
Yeah, I'm ready.
Alright, here we go.
Ok, Steve...
What?
Can you move to your left?
Here?
Yeah, that's good.
And then Matt...
can you just go right in front of Steve?
Here?
Yeah, perfect.
Yeah, yeah. Ok.
This is the ball test.
You ready?
Yep.
What the shit, Steve?
What are you doing?
Get off! Get off!
Underhand.
What are you doing? Underhand.
I tried, man. I tried.
Let's do it. Let's do it.
Alright.
Alright. Wait, wait.
We good?
We said underhand, right?
Yeah, it is underhand.
Ok. Yeah.
You gave it too early
I'm on you.
You're not gonna get me this time.
You ready?
Yeah.
Ok.
I'm on it.
Yeah.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Let's go.
Yeah!
The crowd goes wild!
Yeah, I'm ready. I'm ready.
Alright, Matt.
Beam him. Beam him.
Let's beam him. Beam him.
I'm... I'm going to.
Holy shit!
Hey. Wait, wait, wait.
That's great!
He did it!
I did it! I did it!
That is crazy!
Oh, my God!
Look at it!
Holy shit!
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Oh, dude, you're bleeding.
You're bleeding.
Oh, man, shit.
Stop, stop, stop. Get a tissue.
You did it! Yes!
Alright. Pop-up. Ready?
Yeah.
Yes!
Put on. Put on the music.
Oh, yeah.
Yes.
Matt, you have...
you have to pretend like you're
squeezing them together with your hands.
That's what I'm doing.
Look. That's what I'm doing.
I can't do it, dude...
I give up.
You do it.
You're better at this than I am.
Oh, really? Am I?
Really?
Just do it.
Sick.
Dude, I hate you!
That's...
I'm impressed, man. I am impressed.
That's amazing.
That was awesome, dude.
Oh, no!
Come on, dude.
That is not cool.
What?
My Legos.
You've been hanging out with
those two guys for the last three weeks.
Three weeks.
I'm not stupid.
I think you're hiding something from me.
You better call me back.
I love you.
I'm gonna get a brick through
my window.
I am legitimately scared.
I have an election coming up,
and I don't have time for this.
Dude, why are you asking us
for advice on girls?
Because we're his mistress.
So, what, you think it's,
like, radiation or something?
Radiation from what?
Dude, it's the government.
What?
Matt, what are you talking about?
I'm feeling pretty spelunked out actually.
Andrew, relax.
That's so weird.
It looks completely
different during the day.
Look. I don't care, ok?
I am not going in the hole again.
Asshole.
It's like, sunk in or something.
There goes your old camera, dude.
Oh, shit.
That's weird.
I can still feel it down there.
I can't believe
we made it out of there.
Well,
I mean, that answers that, right?
What does?
We still don't know what happened.
No Well, we're still alive.
Me I was...
Hey!
You kids can't be here, ok?
You got to move on out.
What?
The ground's unstable.
We're taping the whole place off.
Ok. We're going.
Vote for Steve!
New camera's working out for you.
That's good. Yeah,
it's pretty cool, right?
Yeah, smaller.
Does that shoot on tape?
No, it just... It like records
right onto the camera.
No, I just want to record all the
stuff that we can do, you know.
Yeah, but it's like all the time.
You don't feel like it's a little weird,
like it puts a barrier between
you and everything else?
I don't know.
Maybe I want a barrier.
So, like, what's up with your dad?
What's his story, what does he do?
My dad's a firefighter.
Ok, that's cool.
Oh man, that must have been awesome...
Yeah, well he was, I guess.
What happened?
I don't know, he didn't die or anything.
He just got injured
on the job and now he...
he collects the insurance, you know.
So he doesn't really do anything.
He just... He...
He'll go out during the day,
but I don't know where he goes.
He drinks a lot.
I know that much.
I've actually been having
some problems with my parents too.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah I mean, they're nothing like yours.
I mean...
not like that, I just...
Never mind.
They just been fighting a lot lately.
And...
I think my mom is actually
cheating on my dad.
Can you not say anything about that?
Yeah, no way.
Thanks.
Yes.
Karen
Detmer. D-E-T-M-E-R.
Yes.
Thank you.
She's in pain.
She needs something stronger.
Her breathing's worse.
Sir, she's suffering.
Please help me.
I'm on disability.
I can't afford $700.
Please, don't put me on hold!
She can't breathe, ok?
I don't know what to do any more.
Is it on?
Yeah. Yeah. You got it.
I want to remember you like this.
Oh, Mom.
You're stronger than this.
Can you say that for me?
Please?
I'm stronger than this.
Oh, nice.
Alright. Here.
Watch this.
Weak.
Hey, Matt.
Yeah?
Do you like me?
Yeah, of course.
I mean, you know, I didn't...
I mean, you know, I didn't always.
What do you mean?
I don't know.
Like, you haven't...
You haven't always been
super easy to talk to.
You know.
I mean, I'm not saying that...
you're not now. I'm just...
You're such an asshole.
That's what I'm talking about, dude.
You're hostile, see?
Better.
Hey, Matt.
Yeah?
Do you ever think about, like...
doing more with it?
What, with this?
Not really.
Why?
What else is there?
Telekinesis.
Yes. Do tell.
The ability to move, lift, vibrate.
That's my favorite.
Spin, bend, break or impact objects,
through the direct influence of,
mental power or other
nonphysical means..
Ok.
Sounds familiar.
It does sound familiar.
Very familiar.
Yes you want to see direct influence?
Andrew.
She's wearing black today.
Hi.
That's direct influence.
Week, in my room.
Just listen.
I'm just that much stronger,
even last night I got my whole
bed off the ground.
No nose bleed.
Yeah, I've been lifting weights too.
This is my theory though
is that it's like a muscle.
Like it's elastic, if you stretch
it too far, too quick, it'll tear.
That's why I think we're
getting stronger, you know,
because we're working it out,
getting buff.
Buff.
How about this for a workout?
Holy shit!
That was awesome.
Classy.
Attractive.
I think it's time we took this
out of the backyard.
Stop, stop, stop, stop.
Right here. Right here. This is perfect.
Really?
This is it.
Matt. Yah!
Let's get this one.
Hey! Hello!
Hey, what Andrew.
Help!
Somebody grab that!
Stop!
Ok, I'll get the top.
I'll get the top.
Got it. Got it.
Let's get the legs.
Ok. Wait.
I'm flying!
She's just looking at it.
What you looking at, girl?
Stay in school!
Ok, see the guy chewing the gum?
I'm gonna get the gum and pull
it right out of his mouth.
Ok, I got him.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Why are we running for?
We don't need to run.
Five.
I don't want to do it.
Four.
Dude, I don't want to do it.
Three. You're creating a scene.
I don't want to do it.
Come on. Come on, Matt.
Don't be a bitch about it. Just do it.
Put your hand on the table.
Ok. Are you ready?
Do it.
Ok
Give me a countdown.
I will. I promi...
Snap!
Like I said
You got to pay for that now.
Like I said. See?
Holy crap.
Man! Just pretend that there is a
barrier over your hand, right? And then...
When things are gonna
hit you, as long as you're ready,
they will not hurt you
because of the barrier.
That's so sick.
That's me right there.
Steve.
I need that.
Steve. Steve you have to try this, dude.
Give me your hand.
No it's...
When I was a kid though, I actually...
I actually did want to be a police officer.
A cop? No shit?
Yeah. Yeah.
You do know that you can't smoke
weed when you're a cop, right, Matt?
No. Really?
I didn't know.
But, no, I... I... I just...
I really got into, like, altruism.
What does that mean?
What does altruism mean, Matt?
It's like wanting to make things
better for everyone.
Really? This coming from the man who is
always talking about how pointless life is.
Yeah, I know, but this is what
I've been thinking about lately.
Like, I'm looking back,
and I just think...
the way I used to think about things
was probably a lot better, you know.
So, what you want to go out and
start a charity or something?
That's lame.
Wait. Why is that lame?
I don't know.
Douche bag.
I'm not good at everything.
I just do my best at everything.
Alright?
That's what it's about.
I mean, you talk about philosophy
and shit all the time,
but what has he really done?
Have you even applied to colleges yet?
No, but I'm getting...
I'm getting to it.
Yeah, well, you should get to it.
I'm just saying.
I am.
You could use some of that.
You could use some shut the hell up.
How about that?
You just lack initiative.
It's not that big...
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
You lack a dick.
Boys, please tell us
what's going on here.
Well, it would seem that a
Virgin Mary has appeared
in the syrup of a local man's pancake.
No, it has not.
Well, it will in a second, ok?
Just hold on.
Oh, that is definitely some
supernatural shit going on here.
Excuse me.
Can you come here real quick?
Can you just look at that?
Ay, Dios mio!
Grounder.
Too much pressure.
Andrew.
Dude. Come on.
Leave her alone.
Seriously?
Dude!
Oh, come on.
That is so messed up.
She's gonna get fired.
I didn't know...
That is disgusting.
But do you guys share cups on the team?
No, we don't share cups, man.
You see that car though?
The red one.
Yeah.
Alright.
The gum was cool.
Alright. You tried.
It was a failed attempt though.
Watch this.
What are you doing?
Watch.
Go, go, go.
What?
No way!
Holy shit!
Dude! Holy crap!
What? What?
That's what I'm talking about!
Did anybody see?
Steve Montgomery for president!
I'm having like a...
face period.
Oh, man.
Pause.
You guys.
You guys, here she comes.
Here she comes!
Don't look.
Don't look, don't look.
Steve, don't look.
She can't find...
She thinks it's stolen. She it's stolen.
She has no idea.
Yes, it was the black guy this time.
I could have sworn I parked it right here.
Where is my car?
Ignore us.
We're just...
Mormons.
What does that mean?
Garetty's...
Garetty's having a giggle fit.
That was so... It was amazing.
I know. Just take it easy
with the merchandise.
How did nobody see that?
It was out in the open.
Her face!
I cannot get her face out of my mind!
That was awesome.
So many ideas
of stuff that we can do!
Go around.
That's just some redneck asshole.
Steve, Steve, Steve, Steve.
Go around.
Take the camera. Take the camera.
Alright. Just make sure
it's zoomed out all the way.
Got ya. I can see you.
Ok, buddy.
What you gonna do?
What the hell
is this guy's problem?
What are you doing?
Abracadabra!
Andrew, shit!
What the hell did you just do?
Matt, stop the car! Stop! Stop!
Are you crazy? Pull down the road.
We got to go down there right now.
Guys, I'm sorry!
What did you do?
Why? Why did you do that?
I didn't mean to.
I didn't...
Shit!
What the hell is wrong with you?
Look at this!
Will you just calm down!
The guy's probably still in there!
I'm sorry, ok?
Andrew, stop, stop!
But I can... I can help!
I can get him out.
Stop doing things!
Steve! Steve!
Steve, be careful!
Shit! Shit!
Oh, my God, Andrew.
Are you kidding me?
Steve!
Oh, God.
Goddamn it!
Steve!
Andrew!
Shit!
Shit, Shit, Shit, Shit!
Oh, Matt, he's got him!
He's got him. He's got...
Help me.
I'll get in back of him.
Get him up.
Hang on. Steve, stay with him.
I'm gonna go get some help.
Are you calling the cops?
Yeah, yeah.
Will you stop? I can't hear them.
Will you hang up the phone?
Yeah. It's just down past,
White Crescent Bridge.
Matt, he's fine. Matt, he's fine.
Yeah. Yeah.
Fine, Matt!
Stop! Stop! I can't hear...
Hey!
Hey! Hey! Over here!
Peeled off the road and went
straight through the guardrail.
Hey, is that on?
This is a game or something?
I don't understand
how you guys can be so angry.
You don't understand
how we can be angry?
Andrew, you... you put somebody
in the hospital tonight, ok?
Do you understand that?
Andrew, look at me.
You put a guy in the hospital!
How do you feel about that?
You hurt somebody!
Shit.
We need rules, ok?
Rule 1, no using it on living things.
Rule 2, you can't use it
when you're angry, that's it.
Rule 3, I don't think we should be
using it in public or
telling anybody about it.
Look, you can't just declare rules.
Ok?
Ok. I will declare rules...
You're the one that said that nothing matters.
You do something...
I will declare rules.
If we're gonna keep going,
and we're getting stronger,
we need rules.
We need rules, right?
Matt's right. We need rules.
Andrew! Answer the goddamn phone!
Andrew!
Matt, what did he say?
Are you still mad at me?
No, I'm not mad.
Well, you seem mad.
I'm not mad, I just...
I just think that we need to be
more careful now, you know?
We can't...
We have to think a little bit more.
We can't just do things.
We have to think first, ok?
I understand.
Ok.
Why is Steve out in the boonies?
Where are we?
Steve?
His car's right there.
Yeah.
Steve, where you at?
Steve!
Look up.
Hello, boys.
What?
What is up?
No. No. Wait.
Wait, guys. Wait. Check me out.
Wait, hear me out.
Steve.
Hear me out.
You're flying!
Wait, wait, wait.
Hear me out. Hear me out.
No way! No way!
What are you doing?
It's. It's much easier than it looks.
I swear.
It's much easier than it looks.
Oh, my God, dude.
Make sure you catch yourself.
Don't try and jump,
I got it.
Or you'll just flip yourself.
I got it. I got it.
Come on, Matt. Come on.
Alright.
Oh, shit!
Oh man!
Eating dirt, man.
Why don't you get behind me?
You were in my way.
What do you mean, in my way?
Think, think...
Harrier jet. Think Harrier jet.
Oh man.
Goddamn it!
Are you ok?
I'm watching. Ok. Ok.
Just let me concentrate.
Focus! Focus!
Ok! Hold on.
Is that your focus face?
Oh my God, dude.
Bullshit!
I'm up!
Are you kidding me?
Holy crap!
Hold it!
Oh, my God, dude.
Hold it.
Holy crap, dude.
I am doing it.
Yeah! That's it, man.
You're doing it.
Ok. Ok.
Andrew, don't fart.
We'll never find you again.
Steve, stop me.
Stop me, stop me.
Oh, my God.
You are flying now.
You guys look so cute together.
I'm coming up.
I'm bringing the camera, ok?
Alright.
How do we get down?
Andrew!
It's freezing up here!
I can't hear you.
Activate hyperdrive!
Where the hell are we?
Catch up, let's go!
What?
This is insane!
Dude!
Alright, Andrew!
Tag, you're it!
Watch out.
Pump the brakes!
Hey, Matt!
You're finally good at something!
It's so easy!
Yeah!
Got it!
Tebow time, baby!
Nice hands, Steve!
Touchdown!
Throw it back to Daddy!
Oh, dude. Nice catch, man!
Yes!
Steve! Go deep!
Hey, Matt!
Do you hear that?
What is that?
Steve!
Oh, shit. Almost died, dude.
Holy shit. Holy shit.
Almost died, man!
Almost...
Andrew, you saved my life!
Oh, my God.
You saved my life!
Oh, God, you saved my life!
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God! Ok.
Holy shit.
Is that the camera?
You saved me and the camera?
Please tell me you got that on tape!
You have to...
Shit.
What the hell we're alive!
What do you mean?
You didn't see what happened?
Oh, shit! Andrew!
Andrew! You're a genius!
We got to see this!
Holy...
Alright.
Holy shit.
Wait.
Oh, God! We're on the ground.
Yes!
We have broken history!
I mean, I'm talking about
since the caveman times.
The Egyptians, the Wright brothers.
Come here, Matt. Come here.
Get in here. Get in.
Say it. I can fly.
I can fly.
I can fly!
Oh, come on.
Say it with your chest!
I can fly!
Say it, Matt.
Shout it out!
I can fly!
I can fly! I can fly!
I tried to save you, man.
Andrew was just quicker.
How does that go again?
We almost died.
Oh, please.
Gestures...
How does she not notice though?
Come on.
Let's be serious, guys.
She definitely noticed
that it's gotten better.
You just got to be, you know...
Yeah?
You just got to be subtle.
That is so cool.
Dude.
And I haven't had sex since summer.
I haven't had sex since ever.
Really?
That is completely unacceptable.
Well...
How are you guys so cool?
How are you guys so cool, man?
Liquid nitrogen.
Hey, guys?
Guys? You guys up?
Yeah.
Hey...
Today was like...
It was like...
I think, the best day of my life.
Like, I mean...
I'm. I'm thinking about it,
and I can't think of any day,
that I liked better than today,
you know?
I really...
I think it was.
Yeah.
Unanimous.
Yes.
Ok.
Good.
Ok, check this out right.
Say what you want,
but I'm thinking about booking it
to Maui for the weekend.
What's up with that?
Seriously?
Well, we could do it. I mean,
I was thinking the same thing,
except I've always wanted
to go to Tibet.
Why Tibet?
Tibet?
Yeah. I don't know. It's...
It seems really beautiful, you know,
with all the...
Shut up. Shut up?
The monuments and mountains,
you know?
I don't know.
And the monks
have achieved such
a high level of enlightenment,
that they can like,
float and shit, you know?
So we would fit right in.
We could really mess with
their heads as well.
Yeah but like seriously,
I think we should go.
It would be really cool.
Peaceful.
No, I think it's a really good idea.
I actually would like to go.
I'm down.
You down, Steve?
What...
I... I don't know, man.
There's no bikinis in Tibet.
So I don't know if I'm down with that.
It was brilliant.
Oh, it was so amazing.
She might have lost her job.
Oh, shit, dude.
I got my mom's birthday.
I got to go.
It's Aunt Deb's birthday today?
Yeah. I got to go. I got to go.
Tell her I said hi.
Later, Matt.
Alright, what do you want to do now?
Where do you want to go?
I don't know. I mean,
I don't want to go home.
Do you want to go into the city?
Nah, it's rush hour, bro.
It's gonna be so much traffic.
So what?
Oh, yeah. That's right.
Duh! Let's go.
Oh, hey.
Sorry, I just...
Hi.
Do you mind if I film you?
A little bit, I don't really
like being on camera actually.
Well, maybe, you know
it's like exposure therapy.
Yeah.
No, I just I came by to give you
something actually.
You did?
Yeah.
What?
I was watching your...
your... your...
you know, your blog?
There's a drought
in the Central African Republic, right?
Yeah. So I saw that and
I thought it seems pretty cool and...
it's cheap too,
so I thought why not?
Totally.
Yeah.
Yeah, I can tell that you're really,
global and big picture,
concerned about that kind of stuff.
Yeah.
You know, Matt, you can
just mail this yourself.
I'm not your mom.
Ok. I mean, I just...
What is this?
Is this like the new you?
You got too smart to have
fun in eighth grade and...
So now what?
No.
Casey, Casey, Casey,
Casey, Casey, Casey.
Listen, can...
Canl just talk to you for a second?
Can I just tell you something?
I just...
I... I...
I just want you to know I'm not,
you know, who I was now.
You know, I'm cool.
I'm just...
You're cool?
High school popularity just seemed
like this weird backward contest,
and I thought since
I knew that, I could just...
That, that made you better than
everybody else.
No. No, no, no.
I just, I would separate myself from that.
I know what you mean.
I get it.
You get it?
I know it sounds weird.
I just wanted you to know that.
To know that you're cool.
I really screwed this up.
Not as much as you might think.
Really?
Good-bye.
Casey...
I got to go. Bye.
Come on.
Dude!
When did you start doing this?
Like, since when?
What, with the camera?
Yes, with the camera.
I don't know, It's been
a little while, I guess.
See...
I can't do that.
I can't do stuff that requires finesse.
I tried to type my name out yesterday,
and I cracked my keyboard in half.
No, dude. It's really easy.
You just. Ok. You just...
You think that you're holding it.
See, that's what I'm talking
about right there.
What?
You're...
You're always thinking up
new shit that we can do, man.
This is insane.
You know, I mean...
Yeah.
Yeah. Yes. I guess that I am.
Mom's like never home any more.
I mean, you saw how my dad is.
He's just... quiet.
Sits around.
And it's pointless to talk to him
about it because he's got...
nothing to say.
See, it's different,
because you've always had friends,
and people want to talk to you
and be around you.
I never had any of that.
I mean, before this,
I barely even hung out with Matt,
and he's my cousin.
We were close
when we were little but...
I don't know.
In high school, everything changed.
Ever been to the Space Needle?
Yep.
When I was like, five.
It's for tourists.
Well, I don't know.
I mean, I went...
I think I was like, seven...
with my dad one time and...
I don't know.
It was actually a really good day.
You remember that?
Yeah.
Actually, I do.
You know, I've been
meaning to ask you.
Winter break is coming up.
You should do
the talent show with me.
No way.
Why not? It'd be good for you
to get out there, you know.
Meet some people, meet some girls.
Dude, I'm not. it's just not...
What?
Look, I'm just really shy, ok?
And I don't...
I don't even have any talents,
so...
What are you talking about,
you don't have. You have talent.
You've got talent.
Oh, dude, no way.
You look handsome.
Thanks, yes. Steve...
let me borrow some of his clothes
you know to make me...
look cool or whatever.
I'm glad you're spending
so much time with your friends.
Yeah.
Yeah, me too.
Hey.
What?
How are you getting to school?
I don't know what you mean.
Don't bullshit me, you idiot.
Matt doesn't come.
He doesn't drive up.
You leave the house.
Who the hell's giving you rides
to school?
M... Matt.
Alright. You know what?
You're lying.
You're up to something,
and you can't hide it.
You think you can just, slink?
Sneak in, sneak around
my house, smiling?
I'm onto your shit.
How do you
even work this stupid thing?
And we're in business.
Hey.
Hi.
What are you doing here?
I'm filming for the talent show.
Matt Garetty is filming for the talent show.
Yes, I am.
What is this, some kind of
newfound school spirit?
How do you like it?
Being on camera?
I actually don't mind being on camera.
Oh. Here we go.
Ladies and gentlemen,
now coming to the stage.
What, no philosophical comeback for me?
Steve Montgomery.
You're probably gonna
want to get this on camera.
C.V. High, you guys ready
for a talent show?
All my underclassmen, come on.
Make some noise.
That's not loud enough.
How about my upperclassmen?
Come on. Make some noise!
Yeah, Steve!
Let me hear it from my seniors,
class of 2012!
Now I want you guys to give it up for the
young and very talented Mr. Andrew Detmer.
And you're on.
Come on, you all.
What are you guys doing?
Let's go! Let's go, let's go!
Are you playing a prank on your cousin?
That's mean, Matt.
Just watch.
Really?
Good luck!
What's he doing?
Show us some talent!
Nice, Matt.
Fifty-two Pickup!
Pick them up!
No way!
Go, Andrew!
What? What?
Are they gonna walk on that?
What do you think?
He's got it.
He's got it. He's got it.
Easy.
Yeah, you got it.
Holy crap!
Yeah! Cakewalk!
Give it up, give it up, give it up!
Oh, my God.
Andrew is so amazing.
Give it up! Let's go!
Seriously, how are they doing this?
I don't know.
Magic.
That was amazing!
Yeah!
Oh, my God.
I. I can see...
your head is like exploding right now.
What?
This is the beginning of your downfall.
Hubris. Right there.
What's hubris?
No, what does hubris mean, Matt?
Seriously?
What does seriously mean?
What? I'm...
Get in there.
Don't push me, dude. I'm going.
Your fans await.
You're the man of the hour.
Look at this house!
Oh, sick!
Dude, this place looks huge.
I know.
It's enormous. Dude.
Matt! Andrew!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Steve! Oh, my God!
Everybody's freaking out. Come on, man.
Everybody's been waiting for you.
V.I.P. coming through.
Coming through!
Andrew Copperfield
coming through!
Make way, make way.
Matt, come this way.
Drew, over here.
Andrew Detmer's in the house!
How are you feeling?
I'm... I'm... I'm doing good.
Yeah? Are you sure?
Are you sure?
Hey. Hey.
Hello.
Andrew.
Magic is so hot.
Thanks.
So, do you not remember me at all?
Monica, right?
Yes!
Monica.
Setting the camera down.
I'm setting the camera down.
What...
Excuse me.
Have you ever played that, over there?
No. I have never
played that, over there.
No?
Never.
I bet you're good at it.
What, you just throw the ball into the cups?
Yep.
I... I actually could be good
at that right now.
Yeah?
Maybe.
Let's find out.
No, no, no, no, no.
Come on!
What?
Come on.
Ok, ok.
Ok, I'm coming.
I'm coming.
There you are.
Amazing.
That's what I'm talking about.
Hey, where is Andrew anyway?
Andrew's upstairs with the girl
with the pink hair.
What, like, they went together?
That's my boy,
of course they went together.
What are you talking about?
Hey, Andrew.
I hope you're seeing this.
Congratulations, sir.
I just, I wanted you to know, dude...
I mean I was really worried about you
before all this, you know?
But dude,
things are gonna get
so much better for you now.
I really, really feel that.
And I want you to know
I love you, you know?
I love you, man.
It's you and me.
It's Detmer and Garetty,
extended family for life.
Oh, sorry. Sorry.
No man, excuse yourself.
Oh, man.
When did I become the
one who's out here...
Hey, Matt.
Filming myself?
Hey, hey?
Hey, hey Casey.
So what are you filming?
It's just a thing.
It's not like
eye of the storm or anything.
Hey, I wanted to...
I wanted to tell you...
I've really been...
it's been making me think a lot.
I've been kind of
thinking about it in my...
No, I have. Like in my life.
Like I've been thinking if I applied
myself what I could do.
You know I could really,
I could change the world.
I mean, it's really been...
You're drunk.
What?
Hey, Casey?
I've basically been stalking you
since like sophomore year.
Sorry, use of the word stalking.
I shouldn't have said...
You want to get out of here?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Yes. Yes, definitely.
I. I. I have to drop off
the camera first though.
Ok, you guys are getting ready
to witness history, alright?
I'm like a proud dad right now
because behind these doors,
Andrew Detmer becomes a man.
He's a little boy behind there.
He's scared.
He's like a butterfly,
getting ready to emerge...
Oh, God!
From a cocoon or some shit like that.
Disgusting weirdo!
Wait. What? What happened?
Ok.
Is that...
Out of my way now!
Oh, man.
Monica, what happened?
Drew! Drew! It's ok, man.
Don't worry about it.
Look, it happens to the best of us, ok?
Dude you had a little too much to drink...
Buddy.
The hell's going on, dude?
Why are you laughing?
Man, all over my jacket.
Stop. Stop laughing.
What are you talking about?
It's cool, man.
No, it's not cool, Steve. Stop.
Stop what? It's cool, man.
Will you just get out of here?
Get out!
Drew, Drew!
What's your problem?
You think this is funny?
No, I'm not laughing...
Get out!
Dad!
Andrew! Please!
I need my medicine.
Mom's in pain, alright?
She needs her pills!
Where are you?
Dad!
Hoarding a $500 camera,
while your mom dies in there?
I mean, how selfish can you be?
I went through your camera.
What did you see?
Just you being a loser.
You think that those people
are your friends?
They're not.
You're an embarrassment.
You're running around this town,
spending my money.
Look at me when I'm talking to you!
I didn't spend any
of your money, Richard.
Because I don't have a dime to spend.
Every last cent...
Look at me!
Every last cent goes to school for you.
School?
And medication for your mother.
I go to a public school!
And I can't even pay for a goddamn...
You don't pay for a public school, you idiot!
What did you call me?
Did you call me an idiot, you shit?
Did you call me an idiot?
You piece of shit!
Get up.
I said get up!
Get up!
I could crush you, you know that?
Stop it!
Crush you!
Get...
Smile, Matt.
Oh, my God, Matt.
Can we not do the camera thing
right now, please?
What happened?
It just started out of nowhere.
Are you ok?
My head hurts really bad.
That's probably Steve
calling your cell again.
I'll call him back later.
I think it's time to take later...
Matt! Matt! Come on!
Matt! Give me my...
I did not expect this.
Hey! Hey, asshole!
Hey! What are you doing up here?
Just leave me alone, Steve!
You can't be up here, dude.
This isn't safe.
I don't want to talk to anyone.
Bro! What are you doing up here?
Leave me alone!
How did you find me?
I don't know, man.
My nose was bleeding.
I heard your voice or something like...
What the hell
happened to your face?
Nothing, man.
Just leave me alone.
No, dude, that's not nothing.
That... Your dad!
Your dad beat the shit out of you.
He can't do that to you now.
Will you stop acting
like you give a shit?
Dude.
Why are you talking to me like this?
I'm your best friend.
I don't have any friends!
You were never my friend
before any of this.
I hang out with you and Matt,
like every day!
We're supposed to fly around
the world together. Don't you...
Do you remember that?
You think I'm...
Stop! Just stop talking to me!
Why won't you just leave me alone?
Come on, man.
Steve, I'm telling you,
get away from me!
Get away from me now!
Please!
Who, by the power of God,
are safeguarded in faith.
Even though you do not see him now,
you rejoice with an indescribable
and glorious joy...
as you attain the goal of your faith...
the salvation of your soul.
What are you doing?
You filming graves?
I don't get it.
What do you care?
You haven't been returning my calls.
Why aren't you returning my calls?
I've been busy.
No, you haven't.
Why aren't you returning my calls?
I just don't feel like talking.
Turn off the camera.
No.
Andrew.
Andrew, turn off the camera.
Andrew?
How did he get struck by lightning
during a storm with no
recorded lightning strikes?
How?
And they found Steve
out in the middle of a field.
Why would Steve go out in the middle of
a field during a lightning storm, Andrew?
I don't know.
Why? What?
I don't know what happened, Matt!
What?
I don't believe you, ok?
I don't believe you.
I want you to turn off
the camera and talk to me.
Why?
Because I want to have a conversation with you ok.
Don't tell me what to do, Matt.
You can't tell me what to do, Matt.
You just turn your camera off.
Andrew. Shut it off!
Don't ever tell...
Give me. Shut it off!
Get off of me!
Andrew.
Are you joking right now?
Is this a joke to you?
I...
What did you do, Andrew?
What did you do?
Who am I supposed
to tell about this?
Who do I talk to?
Who do I talk to about this?
Why won't you just tell me
what happened, Andrew?
Please believe me, Steve.
Please, it's just I...
I don't know what I did. I...
I lost control, and...
and I'm so sorry.
This thing...
is just becoming a part of me now,
and I don't...
I miss you, Steve.
Andrew!
Dry off!
Hey, Wayne!
Ok, so...
see this one here?
This one I got really clean
because I did this little like...
lasso thing around the root,
you know?
But then these two...
these...
I did not get as good.
See how they're broken?
I think it's because
I got them from the middle,
you know, instead of the root.
Sloppy.
I've been doing a lot of reading,
you know, like online about like...
just like evolution and like...
and natural selection...
and how like,
there is this thing, right?
It is called the apex predator, right?
And basically what this is,
is the strongest animal
in the ecosystem, right?
And, and as human beings,
we are, we're considered
the apex predator,
but only because, like smaller
animals can't feed on us,
because of weapons and stuff, right?
The lion does not feel guilty
when it kills a gazelle, right?
You do not feel guilty
when you squash a fly.
And I think that means something.
I just think that really means something.
This one I got really
clean because I did this little, like,
lasso thing.
Andrew, what happened at school?
I need to go and pick up
my mom's medication!
Oh, yeah?
Ok.
You're gonna break the rules again?
We're too strong for that now, Andrew!
If you did that,
you know what I'd have to do!
You'd have to what?
You have to start thinking Andrew ok?
What would you have to do, Matt?
There are consequences to what you do!
You could not do anything to me
Stop that bullshit! Andrew!
Because I am stronger than you Matt.
I know what you did.
I'm not gonna let you do it again!
I am not going to break your stupid rules!
Ok?
So just screw off and stay out of my life!
I can't breathe.
Thank you.
Karen Detmer.
Just one moment.
We're gonna need a next day delivery.
Co-pay on that is $750.83.
Well, I don't have all that.
Son, I told your dad, and I'll tell you.
You can pay up front, and we
can order next day delivery.
Other than that, I can't help you.
Prick.
I don't give a shit.
Do whatever you want.
Hey.
Hey!
Give me all your money.
What?
Who is that?
Doesn't matter who it is.
Just give me all your money or else.
Or else? Shit, man.
Shit, man. Is that Andrew?
It sounds kind of like Andrew
under there.
And you got Andrew's
broke-ass backpack on.
You got a gat?
I got a gat too, bitch.
Dude!
Come on, come on, come on,
come on, come on, come on!
Come on, come on, come on!
Hey!
The camera needs to stay on
for our investigation.
Jesus Christ.
Can I have a moment alone with my son?
If he regains consciousness,
notify the officer outside.
Yeah, yeah.
Your mother's dead.
She died last night
while I was out looking for you.
I came home and...
she was there in her bed.
If I just could have been there for her.
I was always there for her when
you were out screwing around.
And this one time...
this...
one time...
that she needed me,
and you took me away!
I want you to apologize to me.
I know you can hear me,
so I want you to sit up,
right now,
and apologize to me.
You selfish, selfish asshole!
This is your fault!
You...
Do you hear me?
Your mother is dead,
and it is your fault!
Happy birthday!
Pound it? Pound it?
Go and get a present.
Go and get a present. Yeah.
Yes, the big one.
Oh, my God. Matt.
Matt, your nose again.
Are you ok?
Oh, shit!
Baby, you're really bleeding.
Matt, your nose!
Oh, my God, Matt.
Did you hear that? Did you...
How can you not hear that?
It's so...
Hear what?
What are you hearing?
Something's wrong with Andrew.
We apologize for the delay,
but as of right now,
Oh, my God.
Every news helicopter
in Greater King County
is headed to Seattle.
Again right now,
we have verry little information,
but if appears a bomb has gone off
at Ballard Community Hospital.
Casey, come here. Come here.
Come here. Please. Please.
What?
No, Matt. Are you seeing this?
Where are your keys?
You mean...
Where are your keys at?
What? Matt!
Just stay here, I'll be back.
I just have to drive there, ok?
Please, wait!
I just...
Matt, please!
Listen, Andrew's in trouble, ok?
Please!
Andrew's what?
I'm sure that Andrew is fine.
Andrew needs me! I need to get to the city.
Tell me what's going on.
Shit. Shit I got to get...
Is that a roadblock?
Nobody else is driving this way!
Talk to me!
Casey stop, I need to think, ok?
I got to find another way downtown.
Shit!
Go back and take the Madison exit.
Come on.
Stay here, Casey. Stay here.
Wait!
Matt, wait for me!
All units, report to Ballard
Community Hospital.
Excuse me.
Sir, excuse me.
Matt!
What are we doing here?
Oh, my God!
You got to put me down!
Please! Stop!
You did this to me!
Matt!
Oh, my God!
Holy shit!
Matt!
Casey, we got to go!
We got to go right now!
Get in the car!
Let's go.
Andrew's out of control.
What are you talking about?
I'm so sorry.
I wanted to tell you. I...
Oh, my God, Matt!
Stop the car!
It's gonna crash.
Holy shit!
Oh, shit!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Get off the road now!
Oh, my God!
Hold on to me!
It's not me, it's Andrew!
Hold on!
I can't stop it!
I can't control the car!
I can't control it.
Shit!
Andrew!
Oh, God, hold on!
Hold on to me!
I can't get the door open!
Oh, my God!
Andrew!
Andrew, stop!
Casey!
Matt!
Help me!
Casey, hold on!
Matt.
Stay here. Ok?
You have to stay here. Ok?
Matt, please don't go!
Matt!
We got a car on fire
under the Needle. Possible casualties.
We need emergency response now.
I don't know how to describe this.
That is the Needle we're looking at,
and as you can see, there are...
You're not gonna believe this.
Are you seeing this?
Back away from the window!
What the hell are they doing up there?
Get down!
Seventeen, beware.
You Te gonna ha ve to divert
Andrew!
Andrew, look at me!
This has to stop right now, ok?
This is really, really bad!
Why did you catch him?
Listen! Just focus, ok?
I dropped him!
Why did you catch him?
Andrew, this is not a game!
Do you understand?
You're hurting people.
You're weak, Matt!
You're all weak!
Andrew.
I'm stronger than all of this!
Andrew, listen to me, ok?
Just. Just. I need you to listen.
Just. Just focus for a second.
Do not tell me what to do!
I'm trying to explain.
I got two individuals.
They can't stop us.
It's not too late for us to go.
It is too late! I'm done!
Why?
It's over!
You treated me like shit!
You left me alone!
Andrew, you're not alone up here!
I'm here with you!
I should have been with you all along!
But I'm here now!
And we can stop this right now,
you and me!
Andrew, we can just fly away.
We can get out of here.
We can be family.
Andrew.
Andrew, look at yourself.
This isn't who you are.
I'm an apex predator.
What?
No! No!
Oh my God!
Oh, my gosh!
Call the police!
Andrew, no!
Paul! Paul, stay away from the window!
Ok, ok!
Paul! Don't stand at the window!
Are you seeing this? Hey!
Stay down, babe! Stay down!
Andrew!
Two subjects down.
One injured, one mobile.
Andrew?
Andrew, look at me.
This is all gonna be fine.
You're gonna be alright, ok?
I'm gonna get you help, ok?
All units, respond Code 4 to Denny Way.
Get out of here! It's not safe!
Andrew?
Are you getting this?
Don't move!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Hold on!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
I need help! I need help!
He appears
to be held at gunpoint but...
Oh, my God!
Arms up in the air!
Don't shoot, please!
He's hurt!
Get on the ground!
Wait! Wait!
Do what he says!
Now, get down!
Do not get up!
Get on the ground!
Please don't shoot!
We will shoot you!
I'm not gonna do anything!
The glass!
Take him out!
Leave me alone!
Shit!
We have multiple explosions.
Get in position!
We have them in our sights!
We're covered!
Hold it right there!
No!
Stop!
We have you surrounded!
No!
Hands where we can see them!
Stay down! Stay down!
Stay down!
I repeat, do not move!
Additional units on the far side!
Yo, stay down!
Stay down! Don't move!
Andrew!
Stop!
Don't hurt them! Andrew!
Open fire!
Andrew!
Andrew, stop!
Please, stop!
Andrew!
Don't make me do this!
Stop!
Reports of casualties.
At least two structures
have been destroyed.
I think they're both down!
Two men out.
Show me right now eastbound on...
Yes, sir.
I'm about two blocks away. I see it.
Move up.
Hey! Stop!
What are you doing?
Hey, Andrew.
I just wanted to say,
that...
I'm sorry and...
I... I hope...
that you know that I...
did what I had to do.
You're not a bad person.
I know that.
That's all that matters.
And...
I want you to know that I'm
gonna be better from now on.
I'm gonna help people.
I'm gonna find out
what happened to us down there.
I don't care how long it takes.
I'm gonna get answers.
I'm gonna do it for you,
and I'm gonna do it for Steve.
And...
I just...
I love you, man.
I didn't ever get a chance to tell you,
but I love you.
And guess what.
You made it.
Isn't it beautiful?
Good-bye, Andrew.
By LESAIGNEUR
Sync & corrections April 2020